PATRICK GREEN

Flat 2, 169 Iffley Road, Oxford, OX4 1EL

■M: +447805544791

patrick.green@biodtp.ox.ac.uk

SUMMARY

I am a well-motivated student with a great depth of biological knowledge and research experience and am currently aiming to continue to develop my skills and understanding in the field of molecular plant science by undertaking a PhD.

EDUCATION

DPhil Interdisciplinary Biosciences BBSRC DTP – Oxford University

2018-2022

Master of Science by Research - Bristol University

2017-2018

To continue developing research experience in molecular plant biology and pathology I undertook a

MSc(R) studying Cassava brown streak virus and the role of its HAM1 nuclease on infectivity. A project which introduced me to a wide range of plant molecular and biotechnology methods, such as plasmid cloning, protein purification, agroinfiltration, and protein assays.

Biological Sciences BSc- Durham University (1st class honours)

2014-2017

Having studied a broad range of topics in 1st and 2nd year, I tailored my degree towards Genetics and Biotechnology, with a strong emphasis throughout on plant science research. I completed a literature review microRNA regulation of plant drought responses, and conducted 5 on week research project using infra-red spectrometry to measure different leaf photosynthetic parameters in Digitalis and Impatiens grown at different light intensities.

GCE Advanced level: Hills Road Sixth form - Cambridge

2014

Three A levels: Biology, Chemistry, Maths (A*AA), AS Physics (A)

GCSE: Linton Village College - Linton, Cambridgeshire

2012

10 GCSEs (6 A*'s, 3A's, B)

WORK HISTORY

Buildings and Health and Safety Officer - MedImmune - *Granta Park, Cambridge*

07/2015 - 09/2015

Inspecting labs and performing a chemical inventory

Research Placement - Nuffield Bursary - Cambridge University Department of Genetics

07/2013 - 08/2013

A summer internship assisting research on the effects of epigenetic signals on stem cells and their expression of NANOG gene using GFP expression

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Bristol University Men's lacrosse coach (2017-, Durham University Men's lacrosse 1st team (2014-17)

Collingwood College boat club 1st VIII (2014-16), as well as playing Hockey, Squash, and Cricket as time allows

PADI Qualified Rescue Scuba diver – volunteer as a marine biology research assistant for Frontier Tanzania (2016)

Accomplished Bassoon player - Collingwood College orchestra (2014-15)

Duke of Edinburgh award mentor (2012)

Volunteer leader at Oakley Holidays charity (2013-)

Karate brown belt and instructor (2009-2014)